A Finding Aid to the William Christenberry papers, circa 1917-2018, bulk 1979-2018, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
William Christenberry papers
circa 1917-2018
Archives of American Art
Christenberry, William, 1936-2016
AAA.chriswill
Archival Resource Key
7.3 Linear feet
14.76 Gigabytes
The papers of photographer, painter, sculptor, and educator William Christenberry (1936-2016) measure 7.3 linear feet and 14.76 GB and date from circa 1917-2018, with the bulk of the records dating from 1960-2018. The collection sheds light on Christenberry's career through personal papers, gallery and museum files, professional files, personal business records, printed and digital material, photographs, artwork, and sound and video recordings about his work.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. Access to original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center. Researchers interested in accessing born-digital records or audiovisual recordings in this collection must use access copies. Contact References Services for more information.
Scope and Contents
The papers of photographer, painter, sculptor, and educator William Christenberry (1936-2016) measure 7.3 linear feet and 14.76 GB and date from circa 1917-2018, with the bulk of the records dating from 1960-2018. The collection sheds light on Christenberry's career through personal papers, gallery and museum files, professional files, personal business records, printed and digital material, photographs, artwork, and sound and video recordings about his work.
Personal papers include personal correspondence with friends and family and transcripts of interviews with Christenberry. Gallery and museum files mostly consist of correspondence, price lists, and records of exhibitions. Professional files shed light on Christenbery's relationship with various foundations, colleges and universities, his involvement in the renovation of the John A. Wilson Building in Washington, D.C., and his teaching tenure at the Corcoran College of Art and Design.
Personal business records document purchase of art supplies, and also include correspondence with collectors, sales records, permission forms, and papers concerning fellowships that Christenberry received. Printed materials include newspaper clippings and articles, solo and group exhibition material, and reproductions of Christenberry's work.
Photographs include several series of Christenberry's work and publicity photos of Christenberry. Artwork includes one sketchbook, and project sketches.
Recorded materials consist of sound, video, and digital recordings primarily of footage compiled during the creation of William A. Christenberry, Jr.: A Portrait (1997), produced by Stanley J. Staniski, and the making of The Place I know, Visions of the South (2003).
Related Materials
Also found in the Archives of American Art are an oral history interview with William Christenberry conducted by Merry Foresta, March 3 and 31, 2010, and an oral history interview of William Christenberry conducted by Buck Pennington, January 17, 1983.
Biographical / Historical
Washington, D.C. photographer, painter, sculptor, and educator William Christenberry (1936-2016) was a pioneer in the use of color photography and is known for his images of west-central Alabama and his explorations of the psychology of place.
Originally from Hale County, Alabama, Christenberry had an interest in art and photography from an early age. He earned his B.F.A. and M.F.A. from the University of Alabama and, after graduating in 1959, joined the faculty at his alma mater. After a brief stint in New York where he met Walker Evans, Christenberry took a position as assistant professor of art at Memphis State University in 1962. While in Memphis, Christenberry began exploring color photography more thoroughly while also crafting his own unique style; he also organized a small happening in Memphis in 1965.
Christenberry and his wife moved to Washington D.C. in 1968 where he took a position at the Corcoran College of Art and Design. While living in D.C., Christenberry began photographiing buildings and hand-lettered signs, and photographed other structures and scenes during trips back to Hale County.
Christenberry held solo exhibitions of his work at The Corcoran Gallery of Art, Montgomery Museum of Fine Arts, Philadelphia Museum of Art, The Philips Collection, Palais des Beaux-Arts in Brussels, Belgium, and many more; and participated in group exhibitions such as Visualizing the Blues: Images of the American South, 1962-2000 (2000) at the Ogden Museum of Southern Art, New Orleans, Picturing Modernity (2010) at the San Francisco Museum of Art, and Seeing Now: Photography Since 1960 (2011) at the Baltimore Museum of Art. He received a Guggenheim Fellowship in 1984, an honorary doctoral degree from the University of Alabama in 1998, and several other notable awards for artistic merit. His work may be found in the collections of the J. Paul Getty Museum, Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden, Center for Creative Photography, Birmingham Museum of Art, and many others.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was donated in 2019 by Sandra Christenberry, William Christenberry's widow.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged as 8 series.
Series 1: Personal Papers, circa 1917, 1953-2016 (Box 1; .3 linear feet)
Series 2: Gallery and Museum Files, 1984-2017 (Box 1; .7 linear feet)
Series 3: Professional Files, 1979-2018 (Box 2; .5 linear feet, ER01; 0.263 GB)
Series 4: Personal Business Records, 1979-2017 (Box 2; .3 linear feet)
Series 5: Printed Material, 1947-2017 (Box 2-3, 8; 1.1 linear feet)
Series 6: Photographs, 1958-2012 (Box 3, 8; .4 linear feet, ER02-ER03; 0.275 GB)
Series 7: Artwork, 1965-2000 (Box 3, 8; 4 folders)
Series 8: Recorded Materials, 1980-2009 (Box 4-7; 4 linear feet, ER04-ER12; 14.23 GB)
Interviews; Video recordings; Educators -- Washington (D.C.); Photographers -- Washington (D.C.); Painters -- Washington (D.C.); Sculptors -- Washington (D.C.); Sound recordings; Sketchbooks
- Personal Papers, circa 1917, 1953-2016; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; .3 Linear feet Box 1
  Scope and Contents
  Found here are addresses, museum membership cards, an award and certificate, personal correspondence with friends and family, interview transcripts, a notebook of quotations on art and life, and writings about the artist. Also found in this series are papers concerning an accident Christenberry had as a youth, resulting in a significant loss of vision in one eye. The papers include correspondence, legal documents, and medical records.
  - Addresses, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Award, The Alabama Prize, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Certificate, 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1989-2016; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Family, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Interview with Caldecot Chubb, Transcript, 1978 August 7; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Interview with David Levinthal moderated by Merry Foresta, Transcript, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Interview with Ben R. Sloat, Transcript, 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Membership Cards, 1990s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Notebook, Quotes on Memory, Art, Etc., 1990s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Papers Concerning Christenberry's Eye Injury, 1953-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Papers Concerning "Let Us Now Praise Famous Men", 1971-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Remodeling of Christenberry Residence, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - War Savings Stamps, circa 1917; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Writings, "Sign, Structure, and Cultural Critique: William Christenberry and the South," by M.K. Johnson, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Writings, "The Place of William Christenberry's Early Photographic Work in Contemporary Art," by Alice Brooker, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Writings, "A Homespun American Proust," by Douglas Messerli, 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Writings, "Journey to Alabama with Lee Friedlander," Draft, circa 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Gallery and Museum Files, 1984-2017; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 0.7 Linear feet Box 1
  Files consist primarily of correspondence, price lists, and exhibition material such as checklists, loan forms, clippings, and promotional material. Also found in this series are some inventories and information pertaining to the acquisition of Christenberry's artwork.
  - Adamson Gallery, 1998-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Addison Gallery of American Art, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Anderson Ranch Arts Center, 1997-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Archives of American Art, 1991-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - August Sander Archive, Germany, 1996-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bentley Gallery, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Betty Moody Gallery, 1991-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Birmingham Museum of Art, 1998-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Brooks Museum, 2003-2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Carole Thompson Fine Art and Photographs, 1992-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Center for Creative Photography, 1996-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Contemporary Art Center, New Orleans, 1996-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Contemporary Art Center, Virginia, 1999-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Contemporary Art of Georgia, Museum of, 1998-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Contemporary Photography, Museum of, 1998-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Corkin Shopland Gallery, 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Ehlers Caudill Gallery LTD, 1992-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Genova Palazzo Ducale, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - High Museum of Art, 2002-2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Hood Museum of Art, Dartmouth College, 2002-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Houston, Museum of Fine Arts, 2004-2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Jackson Fine Art, 1986-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - J. Paul Getty Museum, 2005-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Kreeger Museum, 2001-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Lisa Kurtis Gallery, 1992-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Los Angeles County Museum of Art, 2003-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Los Angeles Craft and Folk Art Museum, 2000-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Martin-Gropius-Bau, 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Middendorf Gallery, 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Mobile Museum of Art, 2014-2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Modern Art, Museum of, 1984-2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Montgomery Museum of Fine Arts, 1991-2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Morris Museum of Art, 1996-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Museum Fur Photographie, 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Phillips Collection, 1996-1997, 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Smithsonian American Art Museum, 2004-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Susan Conway Gallery, 1990-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, 2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1991-2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Professional Files, 1979-2018; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 0.5 Linear feet Box 2; 0.263 Gigabytes ER01
  Professional files shed light on Christenberry's relationship with various foundations, colleges, and universities primarily through correspondence, contracts, and printed and digital material. This series contains information pertaining to Christenberry's involvement with the D.C. Commission on the Arts and Humanities on a renovation project of the John A. Wilson Building in the city. Also found here is information related to Christenberry's teaching tenure at the Corcoran College of Art and Design, including correspondence, exhibition materials, position appointments, and material from his celebration of life event. The series also includes scattered materials related to exhibitions and speaking engagements.
  - Aperture Foundation, 1993-2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Colleges and Universities, 1991-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Colleges and Universities, Auburn University, 2004-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Colleges and Universities, University of Central Arkansas, Autobiographical Paper, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Colleges and Universities, Maryland Institute College of Art, 2006-2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Professional, 1979, 1993-2018; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - D.C. Commission on the Arts and Humanities, 2003-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Deutsche Borse Photography Prize. Speech Fragment, 2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - ESOPUS, Project Materials, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Exhibitions, 1993-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - MONO/CHROMATICS (2009), Curated by Christenberry, 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - William Christenberry (2013), MAPFRE, Spain, 2012-2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Federal Reserve Board, Fine Arts Program, 2014-2015; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records, see ER01 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Federal Reserve Board Exhibition, Revisiting Spaces and Places,, Washington, D.C. (2011 March 14-September 16), Digital Video Recording, Archival Resource Key; 0.263 Gigabytes One computer file (Folder ER01)
  - Friends of Photography, 1991-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Hohenberg Materials; Alabama Box, 1982-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Lydhurst Foundation, Retreat, 1998-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - MacArthur Foundation, Nominator, 1999-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - National Millenium Survey, 1998-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Projects, Papers, 1986-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Teaching, Corcoran College of Art and Design, Appointments, 1989-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Teaching, Corcoran College of Art and Design, Administrative Correspondence, 1990-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Teaching, Corcoran College of Art and Design, Exhibitions, 1991-2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Teaching, Corcoran College of Art and Design, Christenberry's Celebration of Life, 2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Thesis Advisor, Ofer Wolberger, 2000-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Wall Construction, Washington Convention Center, 2002-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Personal Business Records, 1979-2017; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; .3 Linear feet Box 2
  Folders may contain receipts, printed material, and other papers related to shipping, materials such as camera film, framing, and printing; correspondence and scant printed material from auctions that featured Christenberry work; correspondence with collectors; sales records; and permission forms. Also found in this series are papers related to Christenberry's Guggenheim Foundation Fellowship from 1984.
  - Art Matters, Inc., 1993-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Artex Fine Art Services, 2013-2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Auction, Photo-Based Art, Inc., 2002, 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Belger Foundation, Collection, 2000-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Bibliography, Christenberry, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Bon A Tirer Prints, 1998-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Collectors, 1991-2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Dodge Color Inc., Invoices, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - E. Ammerman; Price Lists, 1993-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Expenses, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - The Fabric Workshop, 1993-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Film For Classics, 1996-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Guggenheim Foundation, 1984-1985, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Hallmark Cards, Inc., 1991-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Landfall Press, "Adams House in the Black Belt", 1997-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - The Menil Collection, Correspondence and Inventory, 2006-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Model Supplies, 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Mt. Desert Art Program; Marion Stroud, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Nazraeli Press, 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Permissions, 1998, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Sales, 1979-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Ursus Books and Prints, LTD., Purchases, 1994-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Printed Material, 1947-2017; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 1.1 Linear feet Box 2-3, 8
  Found here are several editions of Alabama Magazine from the late 1940s; newspaper clippings and articles regarding Christenberry, his artwork, Alabama and the southern United States, other artists, and miscellaneous topics; and exhibition material from solo and group shows which include announcements, catalogs, brochures, and some posters. Also found in this series are artist cards and examples of Christenberry reproductions as well as publicity material for Christenberry's work with Anna Sloan, Adam's House in the Black Belt (2000).
  - Alabama, The News Magazine of the Deep South, 1947-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Articles and Newspaper Clippings, 1960-2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 49-51)
  - Articles and Newspaper Clippings, Alabama, 1990s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Articles and Newspaper Clippings, Miscellaneous, 1990s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Artist Cards and Reproductions, Christenberry, circa 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Event Materials, 1982-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Exhibition Materials, Solo Shows, Announcements, Invitations, Brochures, Etc., 1970s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 5-7)
  - Exhibition Materials, Solo Shows, Catalogs, 1986-2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8-9)
  - Exhibition Materials, Solo Shows, Catalogs, 1986-2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Exhibition Materials, Group Shows, Announcements, Invitations, Brochures, Etc., 1971-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Exhibition Materials, Group Shows, Catalogs, 1983-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Exhibition Materials, Posters; Calendar Page, 2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Exhibition Materials, Other Artists, 1962-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Galleries and Museums, 1990s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Publications, Art Magazines, 2006-2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Publicity Material, "Adam's House in the Black Belt", circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - "Seeing Patients: The Sketchiest Details," Alan Blum, 2009, 2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - "New American Photographs," Rodger Kingston, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Photographs, 1958-2012; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; .4 Linear feet Box 3, 8; 0.275 Gigabytes ER02-ER03
  Found in this series are images of several series of Christenberry's work, photographs and a digital video recording of an event in 1965, and photographs of the artist used for publicity purposes. Series also includes photos of Christenberry's family and friends, and a residence in Washington, D.C., taken on a Kodak Brownie camera, digital images from a posthumous exhibition in 2017, and slides of work by other artists.
  - Artwork, 5 Cent, Demopolis, Alabama, 1964-1996, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Artwork, China Grove, Hale County, Alabama, 1974-2001, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Artwork, Guinea Church, 1964-2003, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Artwork, "Happening in Memphis", Stills; Sign, 1965, undated; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records, see ER02 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Artwork, "Happening in Memphis" (1965), Digital Video Recording, 2008; Archival Resource Key; 0.243 Gigabytes One computer file (Folder ER02)
  - Artwork, Havana Methodist Church, 1974-1981, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Artwork, "Bama Belle", 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Artwork, 1960s-1990s, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Artwork, 1960s-1990s, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Blue Sky Gallery Thank You from Chris Rauschenberg, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8)
  - Family and Friends, 2004, 2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Members and Award Winners, American Academy of Arts and Letters, 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 8)
  - Publicity, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Residence in Washington, D.C., Taken on Brownie 620, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Studio, 2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Christenberry: In Alabama, exhibition at Mobile Museum of Art, Mobile, AL (2017 March 10-July 9), Digital Photographs, Archival Resource Key; 0.032 Gigabytes 58 computer files (Folder ER03)
  - Images Inspired by Christenberry's Work, 1996, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Slides of Paintings, Other Artists, 1955-1961, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Portrait of Franz Kafka, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Artwork, 1965-2000; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 4 Folders Box 3, 8
  Artwork includes one sketchbook; a small plastic pouch containing dozens of pencil-drawn eyeballs; and project sketches and a small piece of wood from miniature buildings that Christenberry created during his career.
  - Pencil-drawn Eyeballs, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Piece used for Sculptures, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Sketchbook, circa 1965-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 8)
  - Sketches, "Dream Building", circa 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Recorded Materials, 1980-2009; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 4 Linear feet Box 4-7; 14.23 Gigabytes ER04-ER12
  This series includes sound, video, and digital recordings.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged as 3 sub-series.
  8.1: William A. Christenberry, Jr.: A Portrait (1997), Staniski, Stanley J., 1993-1997
  8.2: The Place I know, Visions of the South (2003), 2000-2003
  8.3: Other Recorded Materials, 1995-2009
  - William A. Christenberry, Jr.: A Portrait (1997), Staniski, Stanley J., 1993-1997; 8.1; Archival Resource Key; 2 Linear feet Box 4-5